# Penghui Li

Researcher Zhongguancun Laboratory ☑: lipenghui315@gmail.com

**☆**: https://peng-hui.github.io

#### Research Interests

I am broadly interested in **security and privacy**. My research aims to automatically and efficiently detect security threats, and safeguard services and users from attacks. I have found **over three hundred new vulnerabilities**, resulting in urgent updates in foundational systems such as Linux kernel and GitHub.

#### Education

#### The Chinese University of Hong Kong

Aug. 2019 - July 2023

Doctor of Philosophy, Computer Science and Engineering

Advisor: Professor Wei Meng

GPA: 3.97/4

#### University of Chinese Academy of Sciences

Aug. 2015 - July 2019

Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Science and Technology

GPA: 3.87/4

#### Columbia University

Jan. 2018 - May 2018

Visiting Student, Computer Science and Engineering

#### **Publication**

**Summary**: I have published 10 papers at top-tier conferences in Computer Security (Oakland  $\times$  2, Security  $\times$  2, CCS  $\times$  1), Software Engineering (FSE  $\times$  1, ASE  $\times$  1), Web Systems (WWW  $\times$  2), and Database Systems (VLDB  $\times$  1).

#### [1] SDFuzz: Target States Driven Directed Fuzzing

Penghui Li, Wei Meng, and Chao Zhang
In Proceedings of the 33rd USENIX Security Symposium (Security). Aug. 2024.

#### [2] Testing Graph Database Systems via Graph-Aware Metamorphic Relations

Zeyang Zhuang, <u>Penghui Li</u>, Pingchuan Ma, Wei Meng, and Shuai Wang In Proceedings of the 50th International Conference on Very Large Data Bases (VLDB). Aug. 2024.

# [3] Holistic Concolic Execution for Dynamic Web Applications via Symbolic Interpreter Analysis Penghui Li, Wei Meng, Mingxue Zhang, Chenlin Wang, and Changhua Luo In Proceedings of the 45th IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy (Oakland). May 2024.

# [4] **DDRace: Finding Concurrency UAF Vulnerabilities in Linux Drivers with Directed Fuzzing**Ming Yuan, Bodong Zhao, Penghui Li, Jiashuo Liang, Xinhui Han, Xiapu Luo, and Chao Zhang In Proceedings of the 32nd USENIX Security Symposium (Security). Aug. 2023.

#### [5] SelectFuzz: Efficient Directed Fuzzing with Selective Path Exploration

Changhua Luo, Wei Meng, and Penghui Li

In Proceedings of the 44th IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy (Oakland). May 2023.

#### [6] SEDiff: Scope-Aware Differential Fuzzing to Test Internal Function Models in Symbolic Execution

Penghui Li, Wei Meng, and Kangjie Lu

In Proceedings of the 30th ACM Joint European Software Engineering Conference and Symposium on the Foundations of Software Engineering (ESEC/FSE). Nov. 2022.

# [7] TChecker: Precise Static Inter-Procedural Analysis for Detecting Taint-Style Vulnerabilities in PHP Applications

Changhua Luo, Penghui Li, and Wei Meng

In Proceedings of the 29th ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS). Nov. 2022.

☆ ACM CCS 2022 Best Paper Honorable Mention.

#### [8] Understanding and Detecting Performance Bugs in Markdown Compilers

Penghui Li, Yinxi Liu, and Wei Meng

In Proceedings of the 36th IEEE/ACM International Conference on Automated Software Engineering (ASE). Nov. 2021.

☆ Top 5 Finalist of Best Software Artifact.

#### [9] LChecker: Detecting Loose Comparison Bugs in PHP

Penghui Li and Wei Meng

In Proceedings of the Web Conference (WWW). Apr. 2021.

#### [10] On the Feasibility of Automated Built-in Function Modeling for PHP Symbolic Execution

Penghui Li, Wei Meng, Kangjie Lu, and Changhua Luo

In Proceedings of the Web Conference (WWW). Apr. 2021.

#### **Preprint**

#### [11] FuzzCache: Optimizing Web Application Fuzzing with Software-Based Data Cache

Penghui Li and Mingxue Zhang

Under Review. 2024.

#### Theses

# [12] Detecting Correctness, Security, and Performance Bugs in Software Systems with Automated Analysis and Testing

Penghui Li

Ph.D. Thesis, The Chinese University of Hong Kong. July 2023.

#### [13] Detecting CPU Exhaustion Denial-of-Service Vulnerabilities in Web Applications

Penghui Li

B.Eng. Thesis, University of Chinese Academy of Sciences. June 2019.

## Research Experience

#### **Zhongguancun Laboratory**

Sep. 2023 - Present

Researcher

Tsinghua University Feb. 2022 – Sep. 2022

Visiting Student

Host: Professor Chao Zhang

#### Institute of Information Engineering, Chinese Academy of Sciences

Oct. 2018 - June 2019

Research Intern

Host: Professor Kai Chen

## **Grant Experience**

Project Title: Detecting Memory-Safety Vulnerabilities in Multilingual Software

- No. 14209323, General Research Fund from Hong Kong Research Grants Council, 2023

- Principal investigator: Prof. Wei Meng

- Awarded amount: 1,352,729 HKD

- My role: planned the project and wrote the initial proposal draft under the guidance of the PI

# **Teaching and Mentoring**

#### **Teaching Assistant**

Introduction to Database Systems

Fall 2021

Building Web Applications

Spring 2021

Introduction to Cyber Security

Fall 2019, Fall 2020

Linear Algebra for Engineers

Spring 2020

#### **Research Mentor**

Chenlin Wang Aug. 2023 – Dec. 2024

- Ph.D. student at CUHK
- My role: worked as a collaborator and provided high-level suggestions for his PHP fuzzing project

Zeyang Zhuang Jan. 2023 – July 2023

- Ph.D. student at CUHK
- My role: brainstormed the initial idea of graph database system testing project, worked as a collaborator in the publication of Gamera [2]; guided his practice of the RGC proposal in multilingual software security

Changhua Luo Nov. 2019 – July 2022

- Ph.D. student at CUHK
- My role: mentored the award-winning static analysis project [7]

Yanting Chi Oct. 2021 – May 2022

- Undergraduate student from SJTU

- My role: guided his bachelor's degree thesis on symbolic execution
- Next position: Ph.D. student at University of Minnesota, Twin Cities

Chiho Cheng Oct. 2018 – Apr. 2019

- Undergraduate student from CUHK
- My role: guided the final-year project on PHP static analysis, especially taint analysis

Hoihim Chan Oct. 2018 – Apr. 2019

- Undergraduate student from CUHK
- My role: guided the final-year project on PHP static analysis, especially taint analysis

#### **Awards and Honors**

ACM CCS 2022 Best Paper Honorable Mention	Nov. 2022
HKSAR Reaching Out Award	Apr. 2022
IEEE/ACM ASE 2021 Top 5 Finalist of Best Software Artifact	Nov. 2021
PCCW-HKT Scholarship Nomination	Aug. 2021
GitLab Bug Bounty	May 2021
The Web Conference Student Scholarship	Mar. 2021
GitLab Bug Bounty	Jan. 2021
CUHK Postgraduate Student Scholarship	Aug. 2019 – July 2023
UCAS Merit Student	July 2018
UCAS Merit Student	July 2017
UCAS Outstanding Individual in Research Practice	July 2016

### **Professional Services**

#### **Program Committee Member**

European Conference on Computer Systems (EuroSys), Shadow PC	2024
Workshop on Measurements, Attacks, and Defenses for the Web (MADWeb)	2024
USENIX Security (Security), Artifact Evaluation Committee	2024
The ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS), Artifact Evaluation Committee	2023

#### Reviewer

IEEE Transactions on Dependable and Secure Computing (TDSC) 2023 – 2024

#### **External Reviewer**

ACM SIGSOFT International Symposium on Software Testing and Analysis (ISSTA)

2024

IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy (Oakland)

2023 – 2024

The Annual Computer Security Applications Conference (ACSAC)	2023
The ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS)	2021 – 2022
The Web Conference (WWW)	2020 - 2022
The ACM ASIA Conference on Computer and Communications Security (ASIACCS)	2021 - 2022

### **Open-Source Contributions**

TChecker: a static analysis tool with precise inter-procedural support for identifying taint-style vulnerabilities

- https://github.com/cuhk-seclab/tchecker

SEDiff: a differential fuzzing framework for testing symbolic execution engines

- https://zenodo.org/record/6665380

MdPerfFuzz: an extensible performance bug fuzzer for language compilers

- https://github.com/cuhk-seclab/MdPerfFuzz

XSym: a holistic cross-language symbolic execution engine for PHP-based web applications

- https://github.com/cuhk-seclab/XSym

LChecker: a static detector for PHP loose comparison bugs

- https://github.com/cuhk-seclab/LChecker

## **Selected Vulnerability Findings**

CPU-Exhaustion DoS vulnerabilities

- CVE-2021-22217, CVE-2021-39877

Access Control Vulnerabilities

- CVE-2020-23352, CVE-2020-23353, CVE-2020-23355, CVE-2020-23356, CVE-2020-23357, CVE-2020-23358, CVE-2020-23359, CVE-2020-23360, CVE-2020-23361